House # Y/586, Street # 12, Dhoke Ratta, Rawalpindi · +923485496757 **Husnain_ali409@hotmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/husnainali1· Portfolio : https://husnain409.github.io/husnainali.github.io/**

I am a Game Developer and Gameplay Programmer with a deep passion for video games. I enjoy working on a variety of games and have worked on mobile, VR and AR projects. I am an avid gamer who can critically analyze game mechanics and provide feedback on the creation of video games.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2021 - PRESENT

TEAMLEAD GAME DEVELPOMENT, CANZ STUDIOS

Worked on managing the team of developers, designers and modelers. Guiding them through the process of game development, from conceptualization of the product to the final delivery. Handling accounts, analyzing analytical data and day to day process of team.

JUNE 2019- APRIL 2021

UNREAL ENGINE DEVELOPER, VISIONX

Worked on casual games with Unity Engine for android and iOS platform.

- Wild Run: A casual endless survival game based on polygonal characters and environments.
- **Rush Hour :** One tap hyper casual game.
- Parking Mania : A parking simulator.

Worked on virtual reality and augmented reality projects using Unreal Engine.

- **VR Showroom**: VR walkthrough of a virtual showroom with item description and ability to add items to cart for checkout.
- Apartment Walkthrough: First person walkthrough and showcase of apartment interior.

Worked on web based augmented reality project.

• **3D Model Viewer :** Web based 3D model viewer supporting GLB and GLTF models with environment and lights customizations, AR enabled.

JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2019

UNITY DEVELOPER, GAMBIT STUDIOS

Worked on multiple games projects using Unity 3D.

- **Bike Attack Race**: Endless bike racing game inspired by the classic Road Rash.
- Mini Car Racing: Endless racing game.
- Commando Secret Mission: First person shooting game.
- Sniper Shooting Battle: Sniper based shooting game with custom controls, physics and Al behaviors.
- Robot Rescue: Search and rescue game based on robots.
- Racing Ferocity: Endless car racing game with high quality graphics, custom controls and optimization for low end devices.

Worked as a team lead in various projects.

Managed small group of developers and their tasks.

EDUCATION

2016

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, IQRA UNIVERSITY

2010

INTERMEDIATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, RAWALPINDI COLLEGE OF COMMERCE

2008

MATRICULATION, F.G PUBLIC SECONDARY HIGH SCHOOL

SKILLS

- Unity 3D
- Unreal Engine
- Babylon JS

- C#
- C++
- JavaScript

INTRESTS

- Music
- Gaming
- Movies
- Traveling

REFERENCES

Will be provided on request.